{
  "chapter": 14,
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not treated as one of the 3-Vs in Big data?",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Volume", "Velocity", "Volatility", "Variety"],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "NoSQL databases are designed to process",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Structured data only",
        "Unstructured data only",
        "Both structured and unstructured data",
        "Big size data"
      ],
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following organizations has the biggest contribution in NoSQL database development?",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Apache", "Google", "Amazon", "Facebook"],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "When a user deploys some database application over cloud server and uses the database, the user actually consumes which type of cloud service?",
      "incorrect_answers": ["DBaaS", "SaaS", "PaaS", "IaaS"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "The performance issue for relational database while volume of data becomes huge basically arises because its architecture does not support",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Horizontal scalability",
        "Vertical scalability",
        "BASE theorem",
        "CAP theorem"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "NoSQL databases can scale",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Horizontally",
        "Vertically",
        "Both horizontally and vertically",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Instead of strictly following ACID properties, many NoSQL databases follow",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "CAP theorem",
        "BASE theorem",
        "NoSQL theorem",
        "Big data theorem"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "As per BASE theorem, consistency of data may not reflect instantly after transaction",
      "incorrect_answers": ["True", "False"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following goes along the relational DBaaS model?",
      "incorrect_answers": [
        "Amazon RDS",
        "Oracle Server",
        "HBase",
        "Amazon S3"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "NoSQL database Cassandra was initially developed by",
      "incorrect_answers": ["Google", "Amazon", "Apache", "Facebook"],
      "answer": 4
    }
  ]
}
